Hello everyone welcome to
Learn German in Hindi in the next episode today
we are going to learn German greetings you
want let's start so
before starting with German printing we understand one thing that is
formal and informal conversation so what is
formal and informal conversation
so what is informal conversation mean
when you are talking with your friend
you don't think much you introduce him by saying
what are you doing
where are you coming from and your you are using normal cashew
language whereas when you are
talking with your boss with chakli
you use world your by
what did you do compulsory voting all the
language is used officially so this
is formal vs informal in Hindi so
similarly in German also when you
talk informally you
will use doodh meaning you and when you and Malik talk
then you will use aa meaning ji now
both of us are also formal and in format  Let us see
how to make greetings in these formal formats. So first of all,
when you meet someone for the first
time, minimum meeting spoon, when
friends meet and then when in the mind, like
English, it is like 'Har Love Hum Log Karoge
Badi', if you are meeting this form from some official position, then
depending upon the
time of the day, you will say 'Ghunt Marke Peche'
that 'Guddan Markal' means good morning or '
Gud Anta Ghat' means good day or 'Gud Anta Ghat'
means good evening, okay, whereas if you are
saying bye to someone, your friend
is in the Bible, then 'Rook Children' is
chile'
and if your family is saying bye to
someone, then you will say 'Af leaders' that is
from Twitter, which means loosely translated, 'See you
again', but when
you live in Germany and depending upon all the
time, its variants are a little different, like
where I live in Bayern,
in Bayern, when you say hello to someone, they
say 'Greek' or 'Greek' or 'Because this
approach to Italy has a lot of Italian
influence, so byke  What do we like to do while doing this,
but as long as we are new, we will
use regular expressions only, so we will
say hi to us and bike to these
children, okay, right now, if you meet
someone, if you
meet your friend,
what is the first question and in Hindi, what is
brother, what is going on, as I said, there are
many similarities between Hindi and German,
there is sexy Marathi, you
ask the same in literal German, what is
going on, brother, we get as dear, having a test
year, or in short, biggest,
what is going on, so if someone asks you
what is going on, what will you say, so the
mute is getting along well or good,
good, and if I ask you
how is it going, then you will have to ask him too,
and your Kundiya Kundiya said the same
here also, Avgun, agh, agh, so
how will this promotion happen, let's see if
I need any coach indicator or PK
skin or good and near about this
information, whereas if you meet family, how is it
going, gathered in the we  Gate
80 is not working well, neither is
your OTP here, neither is it my OTP, nor is it my OTP,
okay, again how will it be for me, let me
tell you about it, for this the
court is their, and
good, now if someone asked you how are you doing, you
can answer it by adding it to the list, okay, okay, but
generally we will not do that, who asked how are you doing, okay, we
want to
ask everyone, hi, bye, how are you doing, next important time,
sir, sorry, thank you, okay, so if you want to
say sorry, friend, excuse me in German, then there is
a very big category, or let's see,
annual day, go, uninstall, dicom, unknown
young man, it seems big, but you will use it so many times
that it will automatically become easy, but still,
if you find it a little difficult, then you
can use this toot mian line, it is a
straight line, it is in Sonia school, that
if someone has helped you and is
saying thank you, then now say in German,
dark,
postmaster, meaning thank you, further its payment  It
can be thank you so much thanks all will
be in this field and academic jahar accelerator
accused dum kudi if someone
says thank you to you then you will get this and welcome
in German it is bit or British
or you can also say that
we are happy to find them and help you then
you will make Gairsain deep means
yellow so if someone says you dance then
you will say when Twitter or deep ok so right now
we have revised all the important German
keywords agreed
that we have to do that first of all
if you want to say hi to someone
informally solved for hui a good morning good
evening - ped
hua hai hey if you want to say bye to someone formally
one thing for Malik and Twitter if you want to
ask someone how are you doing for the first time then it has been
informed that Glycerin
Thakur Pawan Diya till now this conversation has been done
formally wicket its non
so group their tap and sip if someone says sorry to
you if you say sorry to someone then you will
say Instagram or Street mix
if you want to say thank you to someone then you will
say  Down game religious and if someone
says thank you to you then you will say beat your
welcome or else happy I hope
you all have understood the German rating properly
if you have any doubt then you
can write in the comment and I will try my best to answer it see you
in the next episode thank you